<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GLOBALIZATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Telecommunication allows for the transmission of data and information over long distances using various types of signaling devices. Early forms of primitive ranged communication, including the use of smoke and signal flags, eventually gave way to telegraphs, and later, the telephone. Scientific research and engineering, particularly in the last 30 years, has led to breakthroughs in our ability to communicate globally. Orbiting satellites now provide a means for the transmission of data even to the most remote areas on Earth. Television, internet, cellular telephones, and GPS are now fully integrated into the daily lives of millions across the world because of telecommunications research.</English>
		<French>[TAB]La télécommunication permet la transmission de données et d'informations sur de longues distances en utilisant différents types de dispositifs de signalisation.Les premières formes de communication primitive à distance, y compris l'utilisation de la fumée et des drapeaux de signal, ont finalement cédé la place aux télégraphes, puis le téléphone.La recherche scientifique et l'ingénierie, en particulier au cours des 30 dernières années, ont conduit à des percées dans notre capacité à communiquer à l'échelle mondiale.Les satellites en orbite fournissent désormais un moyen de transmission de données même aux zones les plus reculées de la Terre.La télévision, Internet, les téléphones cellulaires et les médecins généralistes sont désormais pleinement intégrés dans la vie quotidienne de millions à travers le monde en raison de la recherche sur les télécommunications.</French>
		<German>[TAB]Die Telekommunikation ermöglicht die Übertragung von Daten und Informationen über große Entfernungen unter Verwendung verschiedener Arten von Signalisierungsgeräten.Frühe Formen der primitiven Fernkampfung, einschließlich der Verwendung von Rauch- und Signalflaggen, gaben schließlich Telegraphen und später dem Telefon Platz.Die wissenschaftliche Forschung und Ingenieurwesen, insbesondere in den letzten 30 Jahren, hat zu Durchbrüchen in unserer Fähigkeit geführt, weltweit zu kommunizieren.Durch die Umkreis von Satelliten sind jetzt auch ein Mittel für die Übertragung von Daten auf die am weitesten entfernten Gebiete der Erde dargestellt.Fernsehen, Internet, Mobiltelefone und GPS sind aufgrund der Telekommunikationsforschung jetzt vollständig in das tägliche Leben von Millionen auf der ganzen Welt integriert.</German>
		<Italian>[TAB]La telecomunicazione consente la trasmissione di dati e informazioni su lunghe distanze utilizzando vari tipi di dispositivi di segnalazione.Le prime forme di comunicazione a distanza primitiva, incluso l'uso di fumo e bandiere del segnale, alla fine hanno lasciato il posto ai telegrafi e, successivamente, al telefono.La ricerca scientifica e l'ingegneria, in particolare negli ultimi 30 anni, hanno portato a scoperte nella nostra capacità di comunicare a livello globale.I satelliti orbitanti ora forniscono un mezzo per la trasmissione di dati anche nelle aree più remote della Terra.Televisione, Internet, telefoni cellulari e GPS sono ora completamente integrati nella vita quotidiana di milioni di persone in tutto il mondo a causa della ricerca sulle telecomunicazioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>[TAB]La telecomunicación permite la transmisión de datos e información a largas distancias utilizando varios tipos de dispositivos de señalización.Las primeras formas de comunicación primitiva a distancia, incluido el uso de banderas de humo y señal, finalmente dieron paso a los telégrafos, y más tarde, el teléfono.La investigación e ingeniería científica, particularmente en los últimos 30 años, ha llevado a avances en nuestra capacidad para comunicarnos a nivel mundial.Los satélites en órbita ahora proporcionan un medio para la transmisión de datos incluso a las áreas más remotas de la Tierra.La televisión, Internet, los teléfonos celulares y el GP ahora están completamente integrados en la vida cotidiana de millones en todo el mundo debido a la investigación de telecomunicaciones.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GLOBALIZATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The new electronic interdependence recreates the world in the image of a global village." [PARAGRAPH:1]- Marshall McLuhan</English>
		<French>"La nouvelle interdépendance électronique recrée le monde à l'image d'un village mondial."[PARAGRAPH:1]- Marshall McLuhan</French>
		<German>"Die neue elektronische Interdependenz stellt die Welt im Bild eines globalen Dorfes wieder her."[PARAGRAPH:1]- Marshall McLuhan</German>
		<Italian>"La nuova interdipendenza elettronica ricrea il mondo a immagine di un villaggio globale."[PARAGRAPH:1]- Marshall McLuhan</Italian>
		<Spanish>"La nueva interdependencia electrónica recrea el mundo a la imagen de una aldea global".[PARAGRAPH:1]- Marshall McLuhan</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>